VICTORIA

SUN



ABOUT ME

I am a 24 year old product-focused engineer located in San Francisco and rooming with a beautiful maine coon. My passions are in effective user interface design, quality and robust engineering, and promoting diversity in technology. I'm currently interested in the new generation of front-end technology enabled by React, asynchronous JavaScript, and functional programming.

CONTACT ME



victoria.s.sun@gmail.com



www.victoriasun.io



in www.linkedin.com/in/sunvictorias



www.github.com/victorias

EDUCATION



Massachusetts Institute of Technology, c/o 2014

S.B. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

Relevant Coursework: Multi-modal User Interfaces, User Interface Design and Implementation, Artificial Intelligence, Assisitive Technology, Computation Structures, Algorithms

WORK EXPERIENCE



Front End Engineer · Amplitude Analytics · September 2015 - now

- · Shipped Pathfinder, a graph visualization of stateful event data that helps analytics end-users understand user flows around their product.
- · Developed an entirely new architecture to support the growing needs of the product.
- · Delivered a ground-up redesign with the rest of the front-end team.



Full-Stack Software Engineer · Homejoy · June 2014 - June 2015

- · Architected Homejoy Verticals, whose front-end and database design had to be flexible enough so that the operations team could iterate quickly without engineering or product support.
- · Launched home services such as Handyman, Moving, and Carpet Cleaning in 8 cities including San Francisco and San Jose.
- · Developed tools for operations managers by interviewing them and understanding their needs.



Associate Product Manager Intern · Google, Ads and Commerce · June 2013 - August 2013

- · Created and launched "Answer Ads," a new advertising format that leverages Google's Knowledge Graph to increase conversion and improve targeting.
- · Wrote a complete Product Requirement Document, as well as managed all resources for the project.

THINGS I'M PROUD OF

- · A Day In The Life of a Software Engineer Youtube Video that has over 600,000 views.
- · How I Learned To Stop Worrying and Love Coding Like A Girl, a blog post promoting workplace diversity that has over 2,000 views.
- Invited Speaker and panelist at 2015 HSHacks Women In Technology Panel.
- · David A Chanen Award: for the best written paper in MIT Computer Systems Engineering.